<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>buying tips &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/buying-tips/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Top 5 Tips For First Time Home Buyers</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/top-5-tips-for-first-time-home-buyers/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buying tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=958</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>As a first time home buyer in Nigeria, there is probably news you must have heard and you are on the lookout to stay on the safer side of the deal. Buying your first home can be a time consuming and stressful experience. With the under-listed tips, the journey to buying your first home should [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/top-5-tips-for-first-time-home-buyers/">Top 5 Tips For First Time Home Buyers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a first time home buyer in Nigeria, there is probably news you must have heard and you are on the lookout to stay on the safer side of the deal.</p>
<p>Buying your first home can be a time consuming and stressful experience. With the under-listed tips, the journey to buying your first home should be hassle-free and more fun.</p>
<p>Continue reading for <a href="https://sellerrand.com/top-5-tips-for-first-time-home-buyers/">5 tips for first time home buyers</a>;</p>
<h2>1. Have a budget</h2>
<p>Having a budget will help you stick to your initial plan and negotiate better. For example, if you are interested in a particular property you came across online via a real estate agent website that fits in perfectly to your budget, you can easily negotiate with the agent for similar other properties within your budget range.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t go bankrupt buying a property you really can&#8217;t afford, experienced real estate agents will probably have several other options for you even if your budget is not so big.</p>
<h2>2. Watch out for modern features</h2>
<p>Considering the kind of lifestyle you chose, you should watch out for the features the house currently has and what other features can conveniently fit into space. Popular features for a modern house are an indoor bar, swimming pool, large balcony, spacious walkways and several other.</p>
<p>This will help you to understand what features are allowed in the community and what you can do to enhance your home.</p>
<h2>3. Engage an experienced Realtor</h2>
<p>Realtors are the face of every home buyers and sellers, more importantly, they can greatly influence your home buying experience. An experienced realtor should be an individual who has several years of experience and success as well s understanding of the local market you will love to buy a home.</p>
<p>Most individuals got realtor based on referrals or online research to check through their listings and level of understanding of the real estate market.</p>
<h2>4. Compare pricing options in the area</h2>
<p>Don&#8217;t just rely on your instincts or first deal, take your time to compare between other properties by looking up listings online, via social media, forums or friends and families.</p>
<p>Ensure you do research and make findings on the price of recently sold homes in the place goes for.</p>
<h2>5. Ask for Agent&#8217;s fee</h2>
<p>Most of the time, the agent&#8217;s fee might be the only reason you lose out on a great investment. Before every other serious input such as property inspection, document signing and many more. Consider asking the real estate agent for their service fee, the legal fee to avoid overpricing after closing the deal.</p>
<p>Do you feel it will be too difficult for you to accomplish all of the above listed yourself? Kindly visit sellerrand.com or call us on 08104980498 for more information.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/top-5-tips-for-first-time-home-buyers/">Top 5 Tips For First Time Home Buyers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
