<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>lands in ibeju lekki &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/lands-in-ibeju-lekki/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Reasons You Should Invest In Ibeju Lekki</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/</link>
				<comments>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ibeju lekki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lands in ibeju lekki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekki free trade zone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2500</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Real estate investment across the world is dependent upon location as it determines the value of a real estate property. Investing in real estate in Nigeria has become a lot easier through the establishment of registered and verifiable real estate companies. Ibeju Lekki being one of the most sought after location for real estate investment [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/">5 Reasons You Should Invest In Ibeju Lekki</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Real estate investment across the world is dependent upon location as it determines the value of a real estate property. Investing in real estate in Nigeria has become a lot easier through the establishment of registered and verifiable real estate companies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ibeju Lekki being one of the most sought after location for real estate investment in Nigeria. The first set of real estate investors who bought into the old Maroko are now earning big from their real estate investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As with another metropolis in Lagos, the rate of development projects in Lekki can&#8217;t be compared to any and in this article, I will share some major reasons why you should invest in Ibeju Lekki real estate.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Lekki Free Trade Zone</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lekki Free Trade Zone is a dedicated development facility which covers a total area of about 805 hectares of land in Ibeju Lekki. Lekki Free Trade Zone will provide an ideal platform to open up the diverse market for all investors and enterprises in the world making it a unique landmark of the future development of Lagos state and Nigeria as a whole. The project is divided into north and south and upon completion is expected to accommodate 120,000 people for residential purposes on the north part while the south part of Lekki Free Trade Zone is restricted for commercial purposes.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Lekki International Airport</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lekki International Airport is another great project set to be established within the Lekki Free Trade Zone. Although, there are lots of conversations as to the airport project in Lekki it sure has a lot of advantages on real estate investment in Ibeju Lekki.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Fourth Mainland Bridge</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lagos state is the fastest and most popular business hub in Nigeria, which is one of the reasons for the overwhelming population in Lagos state. The 4th Mainland bridge is a proposed 3km bridge that will connect Lagos mainland to the Island from Ajah axis to Ikorodu hereby reducing the rate of traffic congestion and making life a whole lot easier for residents. Real estate investment for both residential and commercial purposes in the Ibeju Lekki axis will definitely benefit a lot from the project.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Lekki Deep Sea Port</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As included in the Federal Government Economic Recovery and Growth plan is the establishment of a Seaport in Lagos state including Ondo, Ogun, Delta, Akwa Ibom, and Bayelsa. The project is set to be situated in Ibeju Lekki axis and its establishment will boost the development of real estate investments, create more jobs and grow the Nigerian economy through imports and exports.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Developmental Growth</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lagos being one of the fastest growing regions across Africa has become a major concentration point for different types of businesses cutting across restaurants, hospitality, health, recreational and lots others. The monumental boost in the Ibeju Lekki axis will be of a major development to real estate investment for both residential and commercial purposes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The above listed are some of the reasons why <a href="https://sellerrand.com/projects/">real estate investment</a> in Lekki is the best you can get in Nigeria.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/">5 Reasons You Should Invest In Ibeju Lekki</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
