<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>living close to workplace &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/living-close-to-workplace/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Reasons You Should Live Close To Your Work Place</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-live-close-to-your-work-place/</link>
				<comments>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-live-close-to-your-work-place/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 16:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living around workplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living close to workplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living in lagos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2577</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>A survey was carried out and it was found out that 84% of people will choose a job far from their place of abode with 3% pay higher, than another close to where they live without that 3%. That 3% pay amounts to spending several hours on the road, especially if you live in Lagos. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-live-close-to-your-work-place/">5 Reasons You Should Live Close To Your Work Place</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A survey was carried out and it was found out that 84% of people will choose a job far from their place of abode with 3% pay higher, than another close to where they live without that 3%.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">That 3% pay amounts to spending several hours on the road, especially if you live in Lagos. A whole lot could be done at that time. You can&#8217;t do much work or partake in any serious activity in the time you spend on the road and in traffic.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is very important to consider a job close to where you live because to a larger extent it affects your physical and mental health as well as work-life balance.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Here are a few reasons why you should live close to your workplace:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">1. You save money: It is outrageous that most people spend more than half of their salaries on transport fare to work. This excludes the fact that transport fare could increase at any point in time especially during festive periods or raining season.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">2. It takes a toll on your health : Spending hours on the road will expose you to pollution especially in a major city like Lagos that is crowded and densely populated, picture sitting in an airtight, limited space Lagos bus and inhaling the fumes from trucks and cars, that is enough to make you depressed and frustrated.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">3. Stress: the stress is just not worth it. The distance between your workplace and your house affects your mental health and can make you get more frustrated. Residing close to your workplace gives you more time to prepare for work and reduce stress.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">4. Less motivation: you definitely will feel less motivated after going through the journey and possibly traffic before you get to work and it&#8217;s not good for your work even if you are your own employer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">5. Accident prone: When you have to travel so far to work on a daily basis you are more prone to being involved in an accident and several other road hazards.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">6. Reduces your productivity: Considering the hustle and struggle for a vehicle and the many other stress you may encounter on your journey, you may end up not being as productive as you should because of the stress.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You can decide to end all of these unnecessary stress by getting a property close to your workplace.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-live-close-to-your-work-place/">5 Reasons You Should Live Close To Your Work Place</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-live-close-to-your-work-place/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
