<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>home buying &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/home-buying/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Tips To Buying a Home Without Going Broke</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-tips-to-buying-a-home-without-going-broke/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 16:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home buying advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2343</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Buying a home remains one of the greatest achievement in anyone&#8217;s life. It often comes as a surprise when young people invest in real estate or own a home. Owning a home is a really expensive investment especially in the peak areas such as Lagos and Abuja. With the aid of real estate property agencies, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-tips-to-buying-a-home-without-going-broke/">5 Tips To Buying a Home Without Going Broke</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Buying a home remains one of the greatest achievement in anyone&#8217;s life. It often comes as a surprise when young people invest in real estate or own a home.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Owning a home is a really expensive investment especially in the peak areas such as Lagos and Abuja. With the aid of real estate property agencies, you do not need to become a Millionaire before you can successfully become a Landowner or buy your own house.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most real estate property agencies have a convenient payment plan for their projects which allows you to split the payment to a monthly or per annum fee. If you are finding it difficult to own a home due to your financial standing, below are 5 great tips to owning a home without going broke.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Research about the location</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you&#8217;ve never experienced staying in a new settlement or somewhere you don&#8217;t have relatives or familiar faces. The first point of action is to research the neighborhood you want to live and what it has to offer as regards your convenience, work and other future circumstances that may arise.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most of the time, you might end up choosing a location because it is closer to your work but there are several other factors that should be considered before you settle for a location.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Up your saving game</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most of the time, people make the mistake of spending all of their savings to pay for a new house leaving them with nothing to less to furnish their new home.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you can&#8217;t be consistent with your savings, it is advised to partner with a real estate firm that offers down payment plan for your choice properties. No matter how small your paycheck is, if you are not saving enough for your targets, you might have issues paying up for your new home. Most importantly, set a realistic monthly goal you can stick to or partner with friends, family or colleagues to initiate a money-saving culture.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Avoid buying a home you can&#8217;t afford</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Not that you can&#8217;t afford the home in reality but it is advised not to avoid spending everything in your bank account on buying a new home.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">We often get encouraged by the kind of houses that are available in the market as at when we chose to buy. If you work with a real estate agent, they can assist you to figure out the type of home that fits perfectly for your budget. Ask the real estate agents for other fees that might come up along the line.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Consider a Mortgage Plan</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Applying for a mortgage plan helps you to purchase your first home without the hassle. Mortgage plans are most of the times government led to home ownership schemes which allow individuals who are either working with the government, business owners or private employees.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most mortgage plan comes with an interest rate which is fairly considerate considering the flexibility it poses. You should consider the types of plan you qualify for and the payment percentage so you don&#8217;t end up spending more than you bargained.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Take your time</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Buying a house is not a child&#8217;s play and can not be totally delegated to someone else to handle except for trusted real estate company. Whether or now you&#8217;ve been staying in the area for a long time or not, it is advised you walk around the house during the day, rush hour and even night if you have the time. This will give you the necessary information about the house that the agents may not be able to provide an even get you familiar with your new community.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Follow up with people in the community and get to make friends with them while you understudy everything you need to know about the area.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Owning a home of your own is a really smart investment but can be fairly expensive if you don&#8217;t prepare enough or go the right path.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-tips-to-buying-a-home-without-going-broke/">5 Tips To Buying a Home Without Going Broke</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Tips For First Time Home Buyers</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/top-5-tips-for-first-time-home-buyers/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buying tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=958</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>As a first time home buyer in Nigeria, there is probably news you must have heard and you are on the lookout to stay on the safer side of the deal. Buying your first home can be a time consuming and stressful experience. With the under-listed tips, the journey to buying your first home should [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/top-5-tips-for-first-time-home-buyers/">Top 5 Tips For First Time Home Buyers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a first time home buyer in Nigeria, there is probably news you must have heard and you are on the lookout to stay on the safer side of the deal.</p>
<p>Buying your first home can be a time consuming and stressful experience. With the under-listed tips, the journey to buying your first home should be hassle-free and more fun.</p>
<p>Continue reading for <a href="https://sellerrand.com/top-5-tips-for-first-time-home-buyers/">5 tips for first time home buyers</a>;</p>
<h2>1. Have a budget</h2>
<p>Having a budget will help you stick to your initial plan and negotiate better. For example, if you are interested in a particular property you came across online via a real estate agent website that fits in perfectly to your budget, you can easily negotiate with the agent for similar other properties within your budget range.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t go bankrupt buying a property you really can&#8217;t afford, experienced real estate agents will probably have several other options for you even if your budget is not so big.</p>
<h2>2. Watch out for modern features</h2>
<p>Considering the kind of lifestyle you chose, you should watch out for the features the house currently has and what other features can conveniently fit into space. Popular features for a modern house are an indoor bar, swimming pool, large balcony, spacious walkways and several other.</p>
<p>This will help you to understand what features are allowed in the community and what you can do to enhance your home.</p>
<h2>3. Engage an experienced Realtor</h2>
<p>Realtors are the face of every home buyers and sellers, more importantly, they can greatly influence your home buying experience. An experienced realtor should be an individual who has several years of experience and success as well s understanding of the local market you will love to buy a home.</p>
<p>Most individuals got realtor based on referrals or online research to check through their listings and level of understanding of the real estate market.</p>
<h2>4. Compare pricing options in the area</h2>
<p>Don&#8217;t just rely on your instincts or first deal, take your time to compare between other properties by looking up listings online, via social media, forums or friends and families.</p>
<p>Ensure you do research and make findings on the price of recently sold homes in the place goes for.</p>
<h2>5. Ask for Agent&#8217;s fee</h2>
<p>Most of the time, the agent&#8217;s fee might be the only reason you lose out on a great investment. Before every other serious input such as property inspection, document signing and many more. Consider asking the real estate agent for their service fee, the legal fee to avoid overpricing after closing the deal.</p>
<p>Do you feel it will be too difficult for you to accomplish all of the above listed yourself? Kindly visit sellerrand.com or call us on 08104980498 for more information.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/top-5-tips-for-first-time-home-buyers/">Top 5 Tips For First Time Home Buyers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
