<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>buying a house &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/buying-a-house/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How To Buy A Property In Lagos</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/how-to-buy-a-property-in-lagos/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buying a house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=937</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Lagos state remains the choices cities for anyone looking at getting properties in Nigeria. It also remains one of the most attractive cities in Africa and features several commercial outlets. If you are looking at buying a property in Lagos, there are several ways to go about it and step to watch so you don&#8217;t [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/how-to-buy-a-property-in-lagos/">How To Buy A Property In Lagos</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lagos state remains the choices cities for anyone looking at getting properties in Nigeria. It also remains one of the most attractive cities in Africa and features several commercial outlets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are looking at buying a property in Lagos, there are several ways to go about it and step to watch so you don&#8217;t end up wasting your investment. Continue reading this article for <a href="https://sellerrand.com/how-to-buy-a-property-in-lagos/">steps to buying a house in Lagos</a>.</span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<h2><b> Prepare Your Budget</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-940 aligncenter" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/expensive-house-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /><br />
One of the most common mistakes when buying a property in Lagos is not defining what your budget entails in its entirety. It is always advised to clearly spell out how much you are willing to budget for the property to avoid paying more than what you planned earlier. Don&#8217;t forget to make inquiries about the extra spending such as the agent service fee, legal fees etc.</span></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<h2><b> Research about the property</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-941 aligncenter" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Guides-To-Successfully-Buying-Property-2-1024x682-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><br />
You automatically become a real estate investor when you decide to buy a property in Lagos and anywhere else. To get more values for your investment you need to carry some background research about the particular property, potential growth or alternatively outsource the task to specialized property agents like Sellerrand.ng to help you carry out detailed research about your desired properties.</span></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<h2><b> Compare the available properties</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-942" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/property-goals-invest-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When an agents present you with a property offer, take your time to compare the options attached to the property. Location, commercial or residential and as well as investment growth potentials should there be a need for you to sell the property in the future.</span></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<h2><b> Verify documents</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-943 aligncenter" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Non-compliance-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /><br />
Buying a property is a whole lot of investment. Ensure you verify all the available documents, invite your lawyer if you&#8217;ve got one and confirm the validity of the properties you are willing to invest in. You can as well reach out to government agencies such as the Bureau of Lands in Lagos state to confirm if the property is not owned by the government.</span></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<h2><b> Make Payments and Confirm Receipts</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-944 aligncenter" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Two-men-holding-mini-house-in-hands-new-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><br />
Finally, you will be joining the league of real estate investors in Lagos and Nigeria as a whole. At this stage, you can now make payments for the property and confirm the receipts. Don&#8217;t forget to register your newly acquired properties with the government and acquired other certificates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This sounds like a whole lot of tasks you probably wouldn&#8217;t want to do all by yourself.  At Sellerrand, we help prospective investors like you run their property errands. Call Sellerrand on 08107809979, 08104980498 or visit sellerrand.com today.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/how-to-buy-a-property-in-lagos/">How To Buy A Property In Lagos</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
