<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>buying a property &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/buying-a-property/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Important Questions To Ask Before Buying A Land</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-important-questions-to-ask-before-buying-a-land/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buying a land]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buying a property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[land]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2327</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Buying land is a great decision that should be taken very seriously considering the expensive price of lands in choice locations and the financial gains it attracts. Before making an offer whether or not a land investment is the next thing for you, there are several questions you should ask to help make better investment [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-important-questions-to-ask-before-buying-a-land/">5 Important Questions To Ask Before Buying A Land</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Buying land is a great decision that should be taken very seriously considering the expensive price of lands in choice locations and the financial gains it attracts. Before making an offer whether or not a land investment is the next thing for you, there are several questions you should ask to help make better investment decisions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In countries like Nigeria, buying a land seems like a big deal because of the level of complexity involved as well as the availability of genuine real estate agents to help your investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">To help you make better rewarding decisions about your land investment, below are the 5 most important questions you should ask the real estate agents.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. What are the zoning restrictions on the Land?</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Zoning restrictions are popular local law that determines the kind of property structures that are allowed in a particular area.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is advised that you make findings from the government authorities about the local regulations as regards land in other to avoid building structures that are not legally allowed in an area and may probably lead to the demolition of your prestigious properties.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. How is the location?</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Land location is considered to be one of the most important sayings and oldest real estate term as it involves buying of land. To avoid buying land with less or no value, it is advised you put much of your energy into making adequate research about the location of your desired property.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The purpose of buying land should be addressed at the point of purchase, whether you are buying for commercial property or residential property.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. What is the land investment value?</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Not everyone buys land to resell but the most individual that buy into real estate is mainly buying because of the investment value and possible return on investment. The land is a very good investment that could yield up to 100% return on investment within a short period of time.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ask the real estate agent about the investment value and possible growth of the property before you buy land.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Why are you buying the property?</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There are different reasons why people chose to buy land in a particular area, it could be for investment reasons or personal residence. Endeavor to balance on your interest in why you need to buy land in a particular area.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If the land is closer to a tourist attraction site, it may not be a good choice for a residential property because tourist attraction sites tend to have more potentials with commercial property.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. What is the total cost involved?</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In Nigeria, real estate is a big investment and requires lots of money. Make proper findings of the total cost that will be involved along the line so as to help make better decisions with your investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The cost of land is determined by some factors such as the location, size of the land, land title and the agent&#8217;s fee.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-important-questions-to-ask-before-buying-a-land/">5 Important Questions To Ask Before Buying A Land</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
