<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>real estate inspection &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/real-estate-inspection/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What To Look Out For During Property Inspection</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/</link>
				<comments>https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 16:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property inspection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate inspection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2573</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Property inspection if done right is one of the smartest ways of buying the right property that worths your time and money. Whether you&#8217;ve been in the real estate for years or you are just setting out to buy your first home, don&#8217;t underestimate the benefits of home inspection. Going for inspection gives you a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/">What To Look Out For During Property Inspection</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Property inspection if done right is one of the smartest ways of buying the right property that worths your time and money.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Whether you&#8217;ve been in the real estate for years or you are just setting out to buy your first home, don&#8217;t underestimate the benefits of home inspection. Going for inspection gives you a great avenue to see and know every little detail about the property you intend to buy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In this blog article, we&#8217;ve put together the critical things you should watch out for during property inspection. It is advised that you pay close attention to every part of these inspection process to avoid problems.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Roof</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The roof is one of the most important features of a house and it should never be overlooked during an inspection. If you have the strength, you might ask for a ladder and climb the rooftop to see things for yourself. The roof is a major player in keeping the home interior in good shape and considered to be one of the most expensive parts of the house to renovate or replace.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Water Drainage System</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Another issue when it comes to property inspection is to look out for how water flows in and out of the building. Check the gutters and home vicinity to confirm if water outside the building flows away from the house and not towards the building. Take note of the walls too for how water from the rooftop is being disbursed around the building.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Electrical fittings</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The electrical system of the home is another important part that needs close attention. Modern homes now make use of a conduit wiring system where the cables are underground or inside the wall. Check the circuit breakers and test some of the sockets in the bedroom, sitting room, kitchen and get them fixed if there is an issue.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Floor Quality or Tiles</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In Nigeria for example, most homes are made of tile floors unlike other parts of the world where home builders make use of wood, glass and several other types of flooring. For a tiled floor, ensure you check the joint, the tiles on the side, take a closer look at the proportion and walk on it like you own the property already to identify cracks.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Wall Painting</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Similar to the flooring is also the painting of the house, run your hand through the walls to notice peeling paints, check if the outside wall is close to drainage that may damage the wall and weaken the home. It is recommended that you pour water on the building if the inspection office permits that.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">6. Plumbing Work</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Paying close attention to the plumbing system of the home gives you an opportunity to see the water pressure and lots more in action. Ensure the bathtubs, showers, sinks are leak tested during an inspection, you wouldn&#8217;t want to pay for a home where bathroom water can flow through your bedroom.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lastly, it is advised that you ask as many questions as you may have during the inspection because it will give you more understanding into some of the workings of the home judging from the real estate agent&#8217;s knowledge. Some of the fixes you noted down in your inspection report could be easily fixed if you decide to talk to the agent&#8217;s about it rather than making assumptions or ended up with an apartment you will regret.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/">What To Look Out For During Property Inspection</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
