<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>property investment &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/property-investment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>4 Types Of Real Estate Investments</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/4-types-of-real-estate-investments/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 15:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2484</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Real estate is one of the oldest, safest and most popular asset classes however most new investors in real estate have not been enlightened on the types of real estate investments in existence. If you want to make a great deal in real estate investment, you will have to consider the type of property that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/4-types-of-real-estate-investments/">4 Types Of Real Estate Investments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="text-align: justify;">Real estate is one of the oldest, safest and most popular asset classes however most new investors in real estate have not been enlightened on the types of real estate investments in existence.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you want to make a great deal in real estate investment, you will have to consider the type of property that you have in mind to invest in because all types of real estate investment has its benefits and pitfalls, which includes unique cash flow cycles, leasing traditions, and standards of what is considered appropriate.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Therefore you&#8217;ll want to study them well before you start adding them to your property wish list. The four major types of real estate that you can invest in include the following:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>

<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Residential properties</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">They are the most common basic, demanding and essential real estate properties because they comprise the highest number of available properties.
They include but are not limited to: Bungalows, apartments, and houses. The most common is single-family homes. There are also condominiums, duplexes, three storey, high-value homes, and vacation homes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you want to find a great residential property in any given area, find a local agent who is more knowledgeable and would be in the best position to tell you the best residential properties and price in the local area.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>

<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Commercial Properties</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As the name implies these includes but is not limited to shopping centers, strip malls, medical and educational buildings, hotels and offices, single buildings with one large retail outlet and roadside booths and kiosks.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">commercial properties are always in demand in real estate properties. More so they usually provide a stable income to the property owners per annum. Some of the factors identified to determine the demand and value of commercial property are as follows; visibility of the property, people traffic, The socio-economic status and income levels of the people who frequently use the commercial outlet.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>

<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Industrial properties</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">From the word industrial, these include manufacturing buildings and properties. The buildings can be used for either for research, production, as a store/warehouse and distribution of goods.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">These properties generally have less operating costs than other properties. They also have lower management and maintenance costs and vary depending what it&#8217;s being used for. Also, these buildings usually have to be configured and redesigned according to their usage. For example, high ceilings may be necessary if you&#8217;re in search of a production building/ storehouse.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>

<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Landed properties</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">These Includes bare/vacant lands, working farms, and ranches, thereby the owner would either build on it, figure out the kind of structure he/she wants to emerge from the land or leave the bare land as it is i.e probably use it as a means of sustenance or income through farming.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The subcategories within vacant lands include undeveloped, early development or reuse and site assembly.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">having gone through this article you are being advised to choose your real estate investment wisely and remember that each type of property comes with its advantages and disadvantages that will determine your cash flow.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/4-types-of-real-estate-investments/">4 Types Of Real Estate Investments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Most Common Real Estate Scams You Should Know</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-most-common-real-estate-scams-you-should-know/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 08:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property scam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate scams]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2476</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>As with every other investment, real estate investment has its ups and down such as falling scam or not getting the right documents for a property. Real estate investment is considered the least risky and the most lucrative investments in the world. However, it is as well lucrative for fake agents to play on people&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-most-common-real-estate-scams-you-should-know/">5 Most Common Real Estate Scams You Should Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">As with every other investment, real estate investment has its ups and down such as falling scam or not getting the right documents for a property. Real estate investment is considered the least risky and the most lucrative investments in the world. However, it is as well lucrative for fake agents to play on people&#8217;s intelligent and scam them of their hard earned wealth.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Buying a property is considered an expensive investment and careful checks need to be put in place to avoid falling victims of real estate scams. In this article, I will share 5 most common real estate scams and how to easily avoid them.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Online Property Scam</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is often the most common form of real estate scam in recent times. Rental or sales property is advertised at a very low cost that keeps you wondering if the property actually exists. Most of these Ads consist of randomly downloaded pictures from other verified real estate website and common property description just to make someone fall for the scam.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In this type of real estate scam, the fake agents or scammers will always avoid contact with the prospective tenants or buyers until it&#8217;s time to close the lead, they delay calls, postpone sending more details about the property and often times request they meet off-site to discuss the property as against meeting at the actual property.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Due to the little or no entry barrier and the absence of strong regulations as to who can deal with real estate investments, individuals buyers or renters are advised to watch out for this type of scam when dealing in real estate.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Title Fraud</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Title fraud is another common real estate scam everywhere around the world, particularly with sales property. This is a situation whereby an agent tries to convince a property buyer that a property has a certificate of occupancy title when it doesn&#8217;t even have a Governor&#8217;s consent title. It is the hardest form of real estate scam to be broken by just anybody due to its level of complication.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Properties come with different titles which indicate their level of insurance as it relates to the government&#8217;s approval for use. If you chose to buy a property yourself, the best route to protect yourself against this type of scam is to hire a real estate agent that understands the nitty-gritty of the business and has a wide network of other professionals in the industry to verify the land title on your behalf.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Home Improvement Scams</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is a situation whereby a group of people approaches a homeowner to offer home improvement services that will enhance the value of their property should they be interested in selling. They most times use high-pressure sales tactics that leave you wondering if it&#8217;s actually worth the investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For example, they may promise to fix your bathroom, kitchen wares with imported leftover materials from a previous construction job and request for commitment pay or they take their offer to someone else. It is advised that every point of your real estate investment, ensure you deal with the registered company with a verifiable presence both offline and online as this will reduce the level of risk you may encounter.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Property Investment Seminars and Conference</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As funny as this may sound, real estate scams can also come in forms of seminars and property investment courses. It is actually a great move if you consider attending real estate seminars or courses be it a free or paid program.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, real estate scammers take advantage of this seminar to hook individuals into an unstructured real estate investment that makes your money work on its own (is that even possible), it is most times combined of a motivational speaker, a millionaire you know nothing about and an investment expert with no certification.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Some can go as far as charging money for the seminars, coerce attendees into buying their books and often lure people into buying their property investment or get a loan from their partner financial institutions. Check this link for verified real estate seminars and courses you can attend for free.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Overrated Investment Potential</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Be it offline or online, real estate professionals are known to market the value of a property to get anyone into buying the property. This is often predominant in a fast developing neighborhood where there is a forecast growth for real estate investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Take your time to request for inspection, ensure you see clear recent pictures and maybe a video of the property if you can&#8217;t go for a physical inspection.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Do your assignment, research about the neighborhood online, talk to friends about it and hire a trusted real estate agent.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The above-listed are some of the real estate scams you may encounter in your dealing, there are several others we can&#8217;t cover in this article. But remember, hiring a real estate agent to handle this dealing saves your quality time, effort and more importantly, protect you from real estate scams.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-most-common-real-estate-scams-you-should-know/">5 Most Common Real Estate Scams You Should Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
