<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>home buying advice &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/home-buying-advice/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Tips To Buying a Home Without Going Broke</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-tips-to-buying-a-home-without-going-broke/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 16:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home buying advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2343</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Buying a home remains one of the greatest achievement in anyone&#8217;s life. It often comes as a surprise when young people invest in real estate or own a home. Owning a home is a really expensive investment especially in the peak areas such as Lagos and Abuja. With the aid of real estate property agencies, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-tips-to-buying-a-home-without-going-broke/">5 Tips To Buying a Home Without Going Broke</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Buying a home remains one of the greatest achievement in anyone&#8217;s life. It often comes as a surprise when young people invest in real estate or own a home.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Owning a home is a really expensive investment especially in the peak areas such as Lagos and Abuja. With the aid of real estate property agencies, you do not need to become a Millionaire before you can successfully become a Landowner or buy your own house.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most real estate property agencies have a convenient payment plan for their projects which allows you to split the payment to a monthly or per annum fee. If you are finding it difficult to own a home due to your financial standing, below are 5 great tips to owning a home without going broke.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Research about the location</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you&#8217;ve never experienced staying in a new settlement or somewhere you don&#8217;t have relatives or familiar faces. The first point of action is to research the neighborhood you want to live and what it has to offer as regards your convenience, work and other future circumstances that may arise.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most of the time, you might end up choosing a location because it is closer to your work but there are several other factors that should be considered before you settle for a location.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Up your saving game</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most of the time, people make the mistake of spending all of their savings to pay for a new house leaving them with nothing to less to furnish their new home.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you can&#8217;t be consistent with your savings, it is advised to partner with a real estate firm that offers down payment plan for your choice properties. No matter how small your paycheck is, if you are not saving enough for your targets, you might have issues paying up for your new home. Most importantly, set a realistic monthly goal you can stick to or partner with friends, family or colleagues to initiate a money-saving culture.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Avoid buying a home you can&#8217;t afford</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Not that you can&#8217;t afford the home in reality but it is advised not to avoid spending everything in your bank account on buying a new home.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">We often get encouraged by the kind of houses that are available in the market as at when we chose to buy. If you work with a real estate agent, they can assist you to figure out the type of home that fits perfectly for your budget. Ask the real estate agents for other fees that might come up along the line.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Consider a Mortgage Plan</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Applying for a mortgage plan helps you to purchase your first home without the hassle. Mortgage plans are most of the times government led to home ownership schemes which allow individuals who are either working with the government, business owners or private employees.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most mortgage plan comes with an interest rate which is fairly considerate considering the flexibility it poses. You should consider the types of plan you qualify for and the payment percentage so you don&#8217;t end up spending more than you bargained.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Take your time</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Buying a house is not a child&#8217;s play and can not be totally delegated to someone else to handle except for trusted real estate company. Whether or now you&#8217;ve been staying in the area for a long time or not, it is advised you walk around the house during the day, rush hour and even night if you have the time. This will give you the necessary information about the house that the agents may not be able to provide an even get you familiar with your new community.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Follow up with people in the community and get to make friends with them while you understudy everything you need to know about the area.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Owning a home of your own is a really smart investment but can be fairly expensive if you don&#8217;t prepare enough or go the right path.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-tips-to-buying-a-home-without-going-broke/">5 Tips To Buying a Home Without Going Broke</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
