<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>real estate investment &#8211; Sellerrand Realty Limited</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sellerrand.com/tag/real-estate-investment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sellerrand.com</link>
	<description>Nigeria&#039;s Foremost Ingenious Real Estate Business Network</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:11:41 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What To Look Out For During Property Inspection</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/</link>
				<comments>https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 16:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property inspection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate inspection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2573</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Property inspection if done right is one of the smartest ways of buying the right property that worths your time and money. Whether you&#8217;ve been in the real estate for years or you are just setting out to buy your first home, don&#8217;t underestimate the benefits of home inspection. Going for inspection gives you a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/">What To Look Out For During Property Inspection</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Property inspection if done right is one of the smartest ways of buying the right property that worths your time and money.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Whether you&#8217;ve been in the real estate for years or you are just setting out to buy your first home, don&#8217;t underestimate the benefits of home inspection. Going for inspection gives you a great avenue to see and know every little detail about the property you intend to buy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In this blog article, we&#8217;ve put together the critical things you should watch out for during property inspection. It is advised that you pay close attention to every part of these inspection process to avoid problems.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Roof</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The roof is one of the most important features of a house and it should never be overlooked during an inspection. If you have the strength, you might ask for a ladder and climb the rooftop to see things for yourself. The roof is a major player in keeping the home interior in good shape and considered to be one of the most expensive parts of the house to renovate or replace.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Water Drainage System</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Another issue when it comes to property inspection is to look out for how water flows in and out of the building. Check the gutters and home vicinity to confirm if water outside the building flows away from the house and not towards the building. Take note of the walls too for how water from the rooftop is being disbursed around the building.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Electrical fittings</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The electrical system of the home is another important part that needs close attention. Modern homes now make use of a conduit wiring system where the cables are underground or inside the wall. Check the circuit breakers and test some of the sockets in the bedroom, sitting room, kitchen and get them fixed if there is an issue.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Floor Quality or Tiles</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In Nigeria for example, most homes are made of tile floors unlike other parts of the world where home builders make use of wood, glass and several other types of flooring. For a tiled floor, ensure you check the joint, the tiles on the side, take a closer look at the proportion and walk on it like you own the property already to identify cracks.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Wall Painting</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Similar to the flooring is also the painting of the house, run your hand through the walls to notice peeling paints, check if the outside wall is close to drainage that may damage the wall and weaken the home. It is recommended that you pour water on the building if the inspection office permits that.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">6. Plumbing Work</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Paying close attention to the plumbing system of the home gives you an opportunity to see the water pressure and lots more in action. Ensure the bathtubs, showers, sinks are leak tested during an inspection, you wouldn&#8217;t want to pay for a home where bathroom water can flow through your bedroom.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lastly, it is advised that you ask as many questions as you may have during the inspection because it will give you more understanding into some of the workings of the home judging from the real estate agent&#8217;s knowledge. Some of the fixes you noted down in your inspection report could be easily fixed if you decide to talk to the agent&#8217;s about it rather than making assumptions or ended up with an apartment you will regret.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/">What To Look Out For During Property Inspection</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://sellerrand.com/what-to-look-out-for-during-property-inspection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Habits Of Successful Real Estate Agents</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-habits-of-successful-real-estate-agents/</link>
				<comments>https://sellerrand.com/5-habits-of-successful-real-estate-agents/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 14:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate agent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2504</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Real estate industry is big enough for everyone to get in there but not everyone can comfortably make it to the top. The desire to achieve success in your dealings as a real estate agent is one thing and the ability to understand the actions involved in making your desired success a reality is another. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-habits-of-successful-real-estate-agents/">5 Habits Of Successful Real Estate Agents</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">
Real estate industry is big enough for everyone to get in there but not everyone can comfortably make it to the top. The desire to achieve success in your dealings as a real estate agent is one thing and the ability to understand the actions involved in making your desired success a reality is another.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Do you wonder how some real estate agents in Nigeria became an icon?<br />
Find below some important habits you should work on towards becoming a successful real estate agent in Nigeria.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Have a Plan</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Although the real estate industry is so big enough to make you wallow in the dark but having a strong plan will enable you to stand true to your niche. Most of the failures in every real estate deal are as a result of failed plans.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ensure you master a category of the real estate market you are comfortable with, make the necessary connections that will help you grow in your desired niche and carefully draw a plan that works best for different situations.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Embrace Technology</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The essence of technology as it relates to the successful growth of a real estate business cannot be overemphasized in this digital age. Employing digital tools will make it much easier for you to reach your target market and maximize profits.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Be Proactive</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Using a proactive approach in the real estate market is a proven way to achieve success faster. By being proactive in your actions as a real estate agent, you tend to pay more attention to doing things that matter to your business towards generating leads and building a sustainable business model.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Proactive real estate agents don&#8217;t just get leads, they make it a priority to respond to these leads and convert them faster.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Employ Digital Marketing</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Advertising your business online is one of the first approaches towards attaining success as a real estate agent. As a real estate agent, employing the necessary digital marketing strategies makes it easy for you to reach individuals and companies that may need your services. You can liaise with brands that have an online presence via their websites and social media for wider reach.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Learn More</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Real estate is an ever-growing industry and as such requires you as a real estate agent to always learn the newest and best ways to grow your business. Make it a top priority to keep up with the industry trends, read books and attend professional seminars that will help you grow your expertise. Learning more about the real estate market will keep you ahead of your competitors and others in the real estate industry.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Due to the ever-increasing numbers of real estate agents across the country. Getting yourself to the top charts is one of the major responsibilities you should task yourself with to become a successful real estate agent.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-habits-of-successful-real-estate-agents/">5 Habits Of Successful Real Estate Agents</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://sellerrand.com/5-habits-of-successful-real-estate-agents/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Reasons You Should Invest In Ibeju Lekki</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/</link>
				<comments>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ibeju lekki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lands in ibeju lekki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekki free trade zone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2500</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Real estate investment across the world is dependent upon location as it determines the value of a real estate property. Investing in real estate in Nigeria has become a lot easier through the establishment of registered and verifiable real estate companies. Ibeju Lekki being one of the most sought after location for real estate investment [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/">5 Reasons You Should Invest In Ibeju Lekki</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Real estate investment across the world is dependent upon location as it determines the value of a real estate property. Investing in real estate in Nigeria has become a lot easier through the establishment of registered and verifiable real estate companies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ibeju Lekki being one of the most sought after location for real estate investment in Nigeria. The first set of real estate investors who bought into the old Maroko are now earning big from their real estate investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As with another metropolis in Lagos, the rate of development projects in Lekki can&#8217;t be compared to any and in this article, I will share some major reasons why you should invest in Ibeju Lekki real estate.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Lekki Free Trade Zone</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lekki Free Trade Zone is a dedicated development facility which covers a total area of about 805 hectares of land in Ibeju Lekki. Lekki Free Trade Zone will provide an ideal platform to open up the diverse market for all investors and enterprises in the world making it a unique landmark of the future development of Lagos state and Nigeria as a whole. The project is divided into north and south and upon completion is expected to accommodate 120,000 people for residential purposes on the north part while the south part of Lekki Free Trade Zone is restricted for commercial purposes.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Lekki International Airport</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lekki International Airport is another great project set to be established within the Lekki Free Trade Zone. Although, there are lots of conversations as to the airport project in Lekki it sure has a lot of advantages on real estate investment in Ibeju Lekki.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Fourth Mainland Bridge</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lagos state is the fastest and most popular business hub in Nigeria, which is one of the reasons for the overwhelming population in Lagos state. The 4th Mainland bridge is a proposed 3km bridge that will connect Lagos mainland to the Island from Ajah axis to Ikorodu hereby reducing the rate of traffic congestion and making life a whole lot easier for residents. Real estate investment for both residential and commercial purposes in the Ibeju Lekki axis will definitely benefit a lot from the project.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Lekki Deep Sea Port</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As included in the Federal Government Economic Recovery and Growth plan is the establishment of a Seaport in Lagos state including Ondo, Ogun, Delta, Akwa Ibom, and Bayelsa. The project is set to be situated in Ibeju Lekki axis and its establishment will boost the development of real estate investments, create more jobs and grow the Nigerian economy through imports and exports.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Developmental Growth</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lagos being one of the fastest growing regions across Africa has become a major concentration point for different types of businesses cutting across restaurants, hospitality, health, recreational and lots others. The monumental boost in the Ibeju Lekki axis will be of a major development to real estate investment for both residential and commercial purposes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The above listed are some of the reasons why <a href="https://sellerrand.com/projects/">real estate investment</a> in Lekki is the best you can get in Nigeria.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/">5 Reasons You Should Invest In Ibeju Lekki</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://sellerrand.com/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-ibeju-lekki/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Types Of Real Estate Investments</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/4-types-of-real-estate-investments/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 15:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2484</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Real estate is one of the oldest, safest and most popular asset classes however most new investors in real estate have not been enlightened on the types of real estate investments in existence. If you want to make a great deal in real estate investment, you will have to consider the type of property that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/4-types-of-real-estate-investments/">4 Types Of Real Estate Investments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="text-align: justify;">Real estate is one of the oldest, safest and most popular asset classes however most new investors in real estate have not been enlightened on the types of real estate investments in existence.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you want to make a great deal in real estate investment, you will have to consider the type of property that you have in mind to invest in because all types of real estate investment has its benefits and pitfalls, which includes unique cash flow cycles, leasing traditions, and standards of what is considered appropriate.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Therefore you&#8217;ll want to study them well before you start adding them to your property wish list. The four major types of real estate that you can invest in include the following:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>

<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Residential properties</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">They are the most common basic, demanding and essential real estate properties because they comprise the highest number of available properties.
They include but are not limited to: Bungalows, apartments, and houses. The most common is single-family homes. There are also condominiums, duplexes, three storey, high-value homes, and vacation homes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you want to find a great residential property in any given area, find a local agent who is more knowledgeable and would be in the best position to tell you the best residential properties and price in the local area.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>

<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Commercial Properties</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As the name implies these includes but is not limited to shopping centers, strip malls, medical and educational buildings, hotels and offices, single buildings with one large retail outlet and roadside booths and kiosks.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">commercial properties are always in demand in real estate properties. More so they usually provide a stable income to the property owners per annum. Some of the factors identified to determine the demand and value of commercial property are as follows; visibility of the property, people traffic, The socio-economic status and income levels of the people who frequently use the commercial outlet.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>

<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Industrial properties</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">From the word industrial, these include manufacturing buildings and properties. The buildings can be used for either for research, production, as a store/warehouse and distribution of goods.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">These properties generally have less operating costs than other properties. They also have lower management and maintenance costs and vary depending what it&#8217;s being used for. Also, these buildings usually have to be configured and redesigned according to their usage. For example, high ceilings may be necessary if you&#8217;re in search of a production building/ storehouse.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>

<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Landed properties</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">These Includes bare/vacant lands, working farms, and ranches, thereby the owner would either build on it, figure out the kind of structure he/she wants to emerge from the land or leave the bare land as it is i.e probably use it as a means of sustenance or income through farming.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The subcategories within vacant lands include undeveloped, early development or reuse and site assembly.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">having gone through this article you are being advised to choose your real estate investment wisely and remember that each type of property comes with its advantages and disadvantages that will determine your cash flow.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/4-types-of-real-estate-investments/">4 Types Of Real Estate Investments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Most Common Real Estate Scams You Should Know</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-most-common-real-estate-scams-you-should-know/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 08:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property scam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate scams]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2476</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>As with every other investment, real estate investment has its ups and down such as falling scam or not getting the right documents for a property. Real estate investment is considered the least risky and the most lucrative investments in the world. However, it is as well lucrative for fake agents to play on people&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-most-common-real-estate-scams-you-should-know/">5 Most Common Real Estate Scams You Should Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">As with every other investment, real estate investment has its ups and down such as falling scam or not getting the right documents for a property. Real estate investment is considered the least risky and the most lucrative investments in the world. However, it is as well lucrative for fake agents to play on people&#8217;s intelligent and scam them of their hard earned wealth.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Buying a property is considered an expensive investment and careful checks need to be put in place to avoid falling victims of real estate scams. In this article, I will share 5 most common real estate scams and how to easily avoid them.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Online Property Scam</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is often the most common form of real estate scam in recent times. Rental or sales property is advertised at a very low cost that keeps you wondering if the property actually exists. Most of these Ads consist of randomly downloaded pictures from other verified real estate website and common property description just to make someone fall for the scam.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In this type of real estate scam, the fake agents or scammers will always avoid contact with the prospective tenants or buyers until it&#8217;s time to close the lead, they delay calls, postpone sending more details about the property and often times request they meet off-site to discuss the property as against meeting at the actual property.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Due to the little or no entry barrier and the absence of strong regulations as to who can deal with real estate investments, individuals buyers or renters are advised to watch out for this type of scam when dealing in real estate.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Title Fraud</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Title fraud is another common real estate scam everywhere around the world, particularly with sales property. This is a situation whereby an agent tries to convince a property buyer that a property has a certificate of occupancy title when it doesn&#8217;t even have a Governor&#8217;s consent title. It is the hardest form of real estate scam to be broken by just anybody due to its level of complication.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Properties come with different titles which indicate their level of insurance as it relates to the government&#8217;s approval for use. If you chose to buy a property yourself, the best route to protect yourself against this type of scam is to hire a real estate agent that understands the nitty-gritty of the business and has a wide network of other professionals in the industry to verify the land title on your behalf.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Home Improvement Scams</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is a situation whereby a group of people approaches a homeowner to offer home improvement services that will enhance the value of their property should they be interested in selling. They most times use high-pressure sales tactics that leave you wondering if it&#8217;s actually worth the investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For example, they may promise to fix your bathroom, kitchen wares with imported leftover materials from a previous construction job and request for commitment pay or they take their offer to someone else. It is advised that every point of your real estate investment, ensure you deal with the registered company with a verifiable presence both offline and online as this will reduce the level of risk you may encounter.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Property Investment Seminars and Conference</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As funny as this may sound, real estate scams can also come in forms of seminars and property investment courses. It is actually a great move if you consider attending real estate seminars or courses be it a free or paid program.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, real estate scammers take advantage of this seminar to hook individuals into an unstructured real estate investment that makes your money work on its own (is that even possible), it is most times combined of a motivational speaker, a millionaire you know nothing about and an investment expert with no certification.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Some can go as far as charging money for the seminars, coerce attendees into buying their books and often lure people into buying their property investment or get a loan from their partner financial institutions. Check this link for verified real estate seminars and courses you can attend for free.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Overrated Investment Potential</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Be it offline or online, real estate professionals are known to market the value of a property to get anyone into buying the property. This is often predominant in a fast developing neighborhood where there is a forecast growth for real estate investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Take your time to request for inspection, ensure you see clear recent pictures and maybe a video of the property if you can&#8217;t go for a physical inspection.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Do your assignment, research about the neighborhood online, talk to friends about it and hire a trusted real estate agent.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The above-listed are some of the real estate scams you may encounter in your dealing, there are several others we can&#8217;t cover in this article. But remember, hiring a real estate agent to handle this dealing saves your quality time, effort and more importantly, protect you from real estate scams.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-most-common-real-estate-scams-you-should-know/">5 Most Common Real Estate Scams You Should Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Mistakes To Avoid In Real Estate Investment</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/5-mistakes-to-avoid-in-real-estate-investment/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 15:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=2354</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Real estate investment comes with ups and downs and mistakes that often influences decision making. As much as there are lots of information on the internet on how to successfully invest in real estate, little is being shared on how to avoid the common mistakes in real estate investment. Investing in real estate requires some [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-mistakes-to-avoid-in-real-estate-investment/">5 Mistakes To Avoid In Real Estate Investment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Real estate investment comes with ups and downs and mistakes that often influences decision making. As much as there are lots of information on the internet on how to successfully invest in real estate, little is being shared on how to avoid the common mistakes in real estate investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Investing in real estate requires some level of good understanding of the industry, process, and regulations that influence investment decisions in real estate. There is little or no entry barrier for real estate investment but real estate investment sometimes might be a bit challenging.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In this article, I will be sharing 5 common real estate mistakes and how to easily avoid these mistakes when investing your money.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">1. Not Having a Financial Plan</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Becoming a successful real estate investor goes beyond having millions of Naira to play within your account. Take into account your financial status and your budget constraints. There is a probability of 95% failure if you risk planning your budget before you make a real estate investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">To begin with, plan a reasonable budget for your real estate investment based on the available information from professional real estate agents or industry experts. Endeavor to stick to your budgets when checking out real estate offers you are interested in before you make a serious decision.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">2. Not Making Proper Research</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Proper and adequate research is the bedrock of every real estate investment decisions. If you don&#8217;t have a very good knowledge of the real estate industry. you can do a quick online search about some factors such as the location, development plans or alternatively outsource the task to a real estate agent.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The research process includes getting more details about the particular property, and regulations concerning property usage. You can easily avoid this mistake by allocating time to research all potential properties before making investment decisions.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">3. Neglecting Laws and Regulations</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">One of the most painful experience someone may ever experience in their lifetime is watching their own property get demolished for neglection the rules and regulations that bind property investment. Every investment has its regulations, laws, and guidelines that should be strictly adhered to in other to ensure a hassle-free investment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is advisable to take into consideration all the tax regulations, housing laws, and property regulations to avoid irreplaceable disaster with your real estate investment.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">4. Not Hiring Professionals</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If not egos, we all have that feeling which makes us believe we can easily get things done by ourselves. Whether or not this is true of everyone, it doesn&#8217;t apply to real estate investment. Not only is a real estate investment expensive, but it&#8217;s also highly competitive and as such needs expertise to make the right decisions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Before you start throwing money out there trying to fix the least important thing first, consider hiring a professional real estate agent that will walk you through all the process such as searching, negotiation, and paperwork.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">5. Not Having a Goal</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most investors fall the victims of just investing because there is a property for sale. Real estate is not a get rich quick scheme and shouldn&#8217;t be portrayed as one. There is a huge difference between the price of property maintenance, renovation costs and much more before you can put a property for sale at a reasonable price. After setting a realistic goal as to what you would like to achieve with your real estate investment, it is important to discuss your goals with real estate experts to validate your process.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is advised to ask every question possible and avoid being unrealistic with your set goals as well as your budget planning.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/5-mistakes-to-avoid-in-real-estate-investment/">5 Mistakes To Avoid In Real Estate Investment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Buy A Property In Lagos</title>
		<link>https://sellerrand.com/how-to-buy-a-property-in-lagos/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kolapo Imam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buying a house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sellerrand.com/?p=937</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Lagos state remains the choices cities for anyone looking at getting properties in Nigeria. It also remains one of the most attractive cities in Africa and features several commercial outlets. If you are looking at buying a property in Lagos, there are several ways to go about it and step to watch so you don&#8217;t [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/how-to-buy-a-property-in-lagos/">How To Buy A Property In Lagos</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lagos state remains the choices cities for anyone looking at getting properties in Nigeria. It also remains one of the most attractive cities in Africa and features several commercial outlets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are looking at buying a property in Lagos, there are several ways to go about it and step to watch so you don&#8217;t end up wasting your investment. Continue reading this article for <a href="https://sellerrand.com/how-to-buy-a-property-in-lagos/">steps to buying a house in Lagos</a>.</span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<h2><b> Prepare Your Budget</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-940 aligncenter" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/expensive-house-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /><br />
One of the most common mistakes when buying a property in Lagos is not defining what your budget entails in its entirety. It is always advised to clearly spell out how much you are willing to budget for the property to avoid paying more than what you planned earlier. Don&#8217;t forget to make inquiries about the extra spending such as the agent service fee, legal fees etc.</span></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<h2><b> Research about the property</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-941 aligncenter" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Guides-To-Successfully-Buying-Property-2-1024x682-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><br />
You automatically become a real estate investor when you decide to buy a property in Lagos and anywhere else. To get more values for your investment you need to carry some background research about the particular property, potential growth or alternatively outsource the task to specialized property agents like Sellerrand.ng to help you carry out detailed research about your desired properties.</span></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<h2><b> Compare the available properties</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-942" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/property-goals-invest-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When an agents present you with a property offer, take your time to compare the options attached to the property. Location, commercial or residential and as well as investment growth potentials should there be a need for you to sell the property in the future.</span></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<h2><b> Verify documents</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-943 aligncenter" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Non-compliance-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /><br />
Buying a property is a whole lot of investment. Ensure you verify all the available documents, invite your lawyer if you&#8217;ve got one and confirm the validity of the properties you are willing to invest in. You can as well reach out to government agencies such as the Bureau of Lands in Lagos state to confirm if the property is not owned by the government.</span></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<h2><b> Make Payments and Confirm Receipts</b></h2>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img class="size-medium wp-image-944 aligncenter" src="https://sellerrand.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Two-men-holding-mini-house-in-hands-new-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><br />
Finally, you will be joining the league of real estate investors in Lagos and Nigeria as a whole. At this stage, you can now make payments for the property and confirm the receipts. Don&#8217;t forget to register your newly acquired properties with the government and acquired other certificates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This sounds like a whole lot of tasks you probably wouldn&#8217;t want to do all by yourself.  At Sellerrand, we help prospective investors like you run their property errands. Call Sellerrand on 08107809979, 08104980498 or visit sellerrand.com today.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com/how-to-buy-a-property-in-lagos/">How To Buy A Property In Lagos</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://sellerrand.com">Sellerrand Realty Limited</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
